My name is Oliver Queen.
After five years in hell,
I have come home
with only one goal--
to save my city.
Now others have
joined my crusade.
To them, I am Oliver Queen.
But to the rest
of Starling City,
I am someone else.
I am something else.
Previously, on "Arrow"...
지난 이야기...
My name is Amanda Waller,
Mr. Queen.
내 이름은 Amanda Waller 입니다. Mr. Queen
Welcome
to Hong Kong.
홍콩에 온걸 환영합니다.
Amanda Waller
wants you working for her.
Amanda Waller는 당신이 그녀를 위해 일하길 원합니다.
She will have her way.
반드시 그렇게 될거에요.
You're Felicity Smoak.
I know a guy who might
당신이 Felicity Smoak군요.
당신과 같은 재능있는 사람을
be interested in hiring someone
with your expertise.
고용하고 싶어할 만한 사람을 알고있어요.
Apparently there's another
bidder for the company.
회사인수를 원하는 다른 경쟁상대가 있습니다.
Who?
Ray Palmer.
누구요?
What are you
doing here?
여긴 어쩐 일이죠?
No! No! Sara!
Sara!
No! No!
Please!
Felicity,
all I'm trying to do
Felicity 내가 하려는 것들은
is make things
easier on you.
모두 당신을 편하게 해주려는 것들이야.
By having me
completely
우리 통신 시스템을
reconfigure
our phone system?
내가 완전히 뜯어 고쳐놓을 까요?
Do you even know
how difficult it is
다중 회선을 복제해서 해킹에 대비하는게 얼마나
to ping a clone off a hacked
transband multiplex?
힘들지 알아요?
No, but only because you
weren't speaking English just now.
아니, 하지만 네가 전문가니까.
Sara?
I didn't know
where else to take her.
어디로 데려가야할지 모르겠어서.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God! Oh.
What happened?
무슨 일이야?
I couldn't...
나는...
I couldn't
leave her.
나는 그녀를 버려두고 올 수 없었어
We have to--
call--we can...
우리 전화를, 아니 그녀를 데리고
take her
to the hospital!
빨리 병원으로 가야해요.
Ollie. Ollie,
it's not fair!
이건 불공평해!
We just got her
back, it's not fair!
우린 이제서야 그녀를 돌려받았는데, 이건 불공평해!
Come here...
이리 와...
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
We'll take
our position here.
우린 여기에 자리를 잡는다.
Who's your target?
네 목표는 누구지?
I don't have a target--
내겐 목표가 없어.
you do.
네 목표지.
What?
뭐?
Might have escaped
your notice,
내 주의를 피해서 도망가는 걸
but Amanda Waller
doesn't have a sense of humor.
Amanda Waller은 용납하지 않지.
Oh, really?
오, 그래?
Then why'd she drag
me off of Lian Yu
그럼 왜 나를 Lian Yu에서 끌어내서는
and bring me all
the way to Hong Kong
홍콩으로 데려온거지?
to become her hit man?
To become her operative.
그녀의 목적을 위한 청부업자로 삼기 위해서?
Obviously she needs you
for something
분명히 어떤 이유로 그녀는 네가 필요해.
or she wouldn't be threatening
my family to assure your compliance.
아니면 네 협조를 얻어내기 위해 내 가족을
협박까지 할리가 없으니까
The target will be entering
our line any moment.
언제 우리시야에 목표가 보일지몰라
The target will walk 10 paces
through the roof garden
목표는 옥상 정원을 가로질러
and arrive at his hotel suite.
That's your window.
호텔 본관쪽으로 향할거고 지금 보일거야
I see it.
보여.
Now.
지금.
Tommy?
??Arrow 3x02 ??/font>
Sara
Original Air Date on October 14, 2014
♪ Arrow 3x02 ♪
Sara
Original Air Date on October 14, 2014
이전 자막러가 시험이라서 함 만들어 봄 (의역, 오역 제법 많음)
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
You know, Sara used
to have a stuffed animal.
기억하겠지만, Sara는 동물 인형을 갖고 있었어
It was this old,
worn out shark
그건 Sara가 Starling Aquarium에서 구한
that she got
from the Starling Aquarium.
매우 낡은 상어 인형이었는데
Every time something awful
would happen to her,
Sara는 우울한 일이 생길때마다,
I would always find her holding
that stupid little shark
그 우스꽝스러운 낡은 인형을
close to her chest.
끌어안고 있곤 했었어.
And now that my sister's dead,
그리고 이제 Sara는 죽었고,
again the only thing
that I can think about
지금 생각나는 건
is finding that dumb
stuffed animal
그 작은 인형을 찾아서는
and putting it in her arms.
그녀와 함께 묻어줘야 곘다는 거야.
I'm sorry.
You have nothing
to apologize for.
그녀에게 사과할 건 없어.
Hey, whoever
did this,
누가 이런 일을 벌였던 간에,
I'm going
to find them.
내가 반드시 찾아낼거야
We're going to.
우리가 찾아낼거야
When I thought that Sara
died on "The Gambit,"
예전에 Sara가 "The Gambit"에서 너와 함께 죽은줄 알았을땐
the only thing
that I could do
내가 할 수 있는 일이라곤
was scream at the ocean.
바닷가에서 목놓아 우는 것 뿐이었어
I had so much anger and rage,
난 너무 화가났고,
and I didn't know
what to do with it.
그 감정을 주체할 수 없었거든.
But I do now.
하지만 지금.
And I'm going
to help you catch
네가 범인을 잡는 걸 돕겠어
whoever it is that did this.
누가 이런짓을 벌였던지 간에.
You're already helping.
이미 넌 돕고있어.
Laurel...
You told us
where to look.
조사할 장소가 어딘지 알려줬잖아.
I'm just supposed
to sit here and wait?
나 여기 앉아서 기다리고 있으면 되는걸가?
No. Now you take
care of yourself
아니 지금은 너의 가족과
and your family.
스스로를 돌볼때야
Your father is
going to need you.
네 아버지도 너를 필요로 하실거야.
Telling him now,
it would kill him.
아버지에게 얘기한다면, 감당하지 못하실거야.
At least now if we wait until
we catch whoever did this,
범인을 찾아내고 말씀드리는게
it'll be easier on him.
차라리 나을 거 같아.
Ok.
그래.
Where are you going?
어디로 가?
I don't know.
I don't know anything anymore.
모르겠어. 이젠 아무생각이 없어.
But I know that a bar is the last
place I should be.
단지 지금은 바에 가서 마음을 추스리는게 나을 거 같아.
Come on, pick up.
받아라..
You've reached Thea.
Leave a message.
Thea 입니다. 메시지를 남겨주세요.
Thea, it's Oliver.
Thea, 오빠야
Um...
I know you're still
traveling,
지금도 여행중일텐데
but I just,
I could really...
그냥, 나는...
I'd really like
to hear your voice.
네 목소리가 듣고 싶어서
So please call me back.
그러니 제발 전화해 줘.
What'd we get off
the cameras?
CC TV에서 건진거는?
Place is
a drug haven.
장소가 마약거래가 넘쳐나는 곳이라
They've all
either been disabled
대부분 동작하지가 않거나
or paint-balled
by local dealers.
지역 딜러들이 페인트를 칠해서..
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Where it
happened.
Sara가 죽은 곳
Felicity told me.
Felicity가 얘기해줬어
You ok?
괜찮아?
Killer stood there,
살인자가 서있던 곳이 여기야,
loose gravel
on the rooftop.
옥상의 자랍을 밟고서서
Oliver...
Sara was here.
Sara는 여기 있었고
Scuff marks
back to the edge.
모서리 쪽에 흠집이 있어.
You don't have to do this
right now, man.
지금 당장 조사할 필요는 없어.
It's the only thing
that I can do.
내가 할 수 있는 건 이것뿐이야
Listen, I get it.
Military training.
이봐, 알겠어. 나도 군사교육할 때 들었었지
Stay on task.
임무에 충실해라.
Your friend gets shot,
you just keep fighting.
네 친구가 화살을 맞고,
넌 복수를 위해 싸우려 하고
But Oliver...
I'm fine.
하지만 Oliver...
난 괜찮아.
Well, I'm here
for you just the same.
좌우간, 나도 같은 이유로 여기에 왔어.
Listen, Sara was
my friend, too.
Sara는 내 친구기도 했으니까.
And if you think you're going after
the person who did this solo,
그리고 지금 니가 누가 범인인지 혼자서 찾겠다면
you couldn't possibly
be more wrong.
넌 정말 잘 못 생각하고 있는거야.
Yeah?
여보세요?
Detective Lance called,
he says it's important.
Lance 경감님이 중요한 일이라고 전화했었어요
Do you think
he knows about Sara?
Sara가 죽은 걸 아시는걸까요?
What is it, Detective?
무슨 일이시죠, 경감님?
You ok? You look like someone peed
in your cornflakes.
괜찮은가? 뭔가 당혹스러워 보이는데...
That kind of day, huh?
그런 날인가?
What's going on?
무슨 일인가요?
Another archer
in town.
또 다른 궁수가 도시에 있어.
Dropping bodies.
시체를 쌓아가고 있어.
Seen this guy's work before?
I might have.
이런 걸 본 적 있나?
있는 듯도 하군요.
You know where
SCPD's finest might find him?
범인이 있을만한 곳을 알고 있나?
Who's the victim?
John Burke.
희생자는 누군가요?
Some corporate
financier from Qurac.
Qurac이라는 회사 재무팀에서 일하고 있지
Seems like he wandered into
the wrong part of town
도시의 위험한 데서 길을 잃은 것 같아.
tonight looking
for a little local "entertainment."
오늘 밤 재미좀 보려고 돌아다닌 듯한데
He ended up with an arrow
to the chest.
그러다 결국 화살을 맞고 끝나버렸지
Hey.
You watch your back,
all right? Whoever this guy is...
조심해, 알겠지?
이자가 누구던간에...
He's a killer.
그는 살인자입니다.
Her hands are so small.
전에는 몰랐었는데
I never noticed before.
그녀는 손이 정말 작았네요
She was always so strong
and brave.
그녀는 항상 강하고 용감했는데.
I always envisioned her
as this sort of
난 항상 그녀가 아마존의
Amazonian warrior.
여전사 같다고 생각했었는데.
Invincible.
내가 절대 될 수 없을
Something I could
never be.
그런 강한 존재라고
I was so jealous.
그녀를 질투하기도 하고
Hi. I know I was
supposed to come into work today.
여보세요, 오늘 출근하기로 한건 알고 있는데
I--the--I'm sorry.
난 정말.. 죄송해요
There's been a death
in the family.
집안에 안 좋은 일이 있어서
Thank you.
감사합니다.
You have any idea what other archer
could have done this?
다른 궁수가 왜 이런 짓을 했을까?
There aren't that many of us.
우리같은 궁수가 많지는 않아.
Maybe 10 that I know of,
내가 알기론 10명??
and most of them are in
the League of Assassins.
대부분은 League of Assassin에 속해있지
Oliver,
you don't think...
설마..
No. No.
They don't
target their own.
그들은 자기네 멤버를 목표로 삼지는 않아
What'd you find out?
He hit again.
뭐 알아낸건?
또다시 살인이 벌어졌어요.
An abandoned warehouse
on the corner of Third and Lemire.
장속는 버려진 창고건물 9층 구석이고
Ninth floor. The victim was a construction
foreman, Tim Kaufman.
피해자는 현장 건설 감독인 Tim Kaufman.
Security cameras
can't get an angle.
보안카메라에는 잡히지 않는 곳이에요.
Who's that?
Just some low level dealers
누구지?
창고에서 마약을 파려는
that set up shop
in abandoned warehouses.
별볼일없는 마약상 같은데
Doesn't look like
much of an archer to me.
그 궁수는 아닌 것 같아.
- He might be a witness.
- Where do you want me?
- 그가 목격자일 수 있겠군
- 어디로 갈까요?
Will Lyla give you access
to A.R.G.U.S.'s database?
Lyla가 ARGUS 데이타 베이스 접속을 허용해 줄까?
To find out who did this, Lyla
will give us access to A.R.G.U.S.
Sara를 죽인 범인을 찾을 수 있게,
Lyla가 ARGUS 데이타 베이스 접근을 허용해 줄거야
I need a list of everyone
on their radar--
그들이 알고 있는 활을 무기로 하는
assassins and mercenaries
who use a bow.
모든 암살자와 용병에 대한 리스트가 필요해
I'm on it.
알아볼께.
What?
왜?
Uh, Thea hasn't
called back yet.
Thea에게 아직도 전화가 없어.
You didn't
eliminate the target!
목표를 제거했어야지
That's not a target,
that's my best friend!
목표가 아니라 내 가장 친한 친구였어
Why am I pointing a gun
at my best friend?
왜 내가 내 가장 친한 친구를 겨눠야 하지?
Is this
some sort of test?
무슨 테스트인건가?
Yes. One you failed!
그래 니가 실패한 테스트지!
Good. Flunk me.
좋아, 날 낙제시켜.
You think it's a coincidence
your friend just happened
네 친구가 홍콩에 갑작스레 나타난게
to show up in Hong Kong?
정말 우연이라고 생각해?
He's here looking for you!
What?
그는 널 찾으러 온거야!
뭐?
When you logged into your email,
it set off an account alert.
니가 이메일을 보내기 위해 로그인 했을때,
알람으로 그에게 알려진거지
Dead men don't check
their email, Oliver.
죽은사람이 자기 메일을 확인할 수는 없으니까
Oh, so this is
my fault?
아, 그래서 내 잘못이다?
Waller needs you.
She can't let you be compromised
Waller는 널 필요로 해
그녀는 갑작스레 홍콩으로 널 찾아온
by some rich kid flashing
your picture all over Hong Kong.
부잣집 도련님때문에 네가 그녀의 계획을 망치길 원치 않아
Whether you're the one
who pulls the trigger or not,
니가 방아쇠를 당기건 말건간에,
she wants Tommy Merlyn
off the board.
그녀는 Tommy Merlyn를 없앨거야.
That is a cobalt
encrypted workstation.
그건 암호화된 컴퓨터에요.
You better not be
using it to Tweet.
트윗질하는데 쓰이는 물건이 아니고
I was--I was,
um, actually just...
나는... 나는, 어 단지...
Accessing an FBI database?
What...
FBI 데이타 베이스에 접속을.. 이 무슨...
Roy, why are you
looking for Thea?
Roy, 왜 Thea를 찾는거죠?
Because I don't think she is where
she says she is.
왜냐하면 그녀가 간다고 했던 곳과 그녀가 있는 곳이 다른거 같아요
Why would she lie?
Thea가 왜 거짓말을 했을까요?
Roy, Oliver needs to see this.
Roy, Oliver에게 보여줘야겠어요
No. This is my fault.
He's going to kill me.
안돼요. 다 내 잘못이에요.
그가 날 죽일거에요.
What if she's in trouble?
What if she's not?
만약 Thea가 트러블에 휘말렸다면?
만약 Thea가 단지 여유가 필요하고
What if she just
needs space?
별일 없는 거라면?
She's had five months
그녀는 5개월간 나가서는
and thousands
of miles of space.
충분한 여유를 가졌을 거에요
Oliver needs to see this.
Oliver에게 반드시 보여줘야 겠어요.
You need to show it to him.
당신이 직접 보여줘요.
You have got to be kidding me.
이런 말도 안되는
What--where
are you going?
뭐, 어디 가는 거에요?
There's someone
I need to kill.
죽여버릴 사람이 있어요
Did you do it to make a point?
그렇게 당신 하고싶은 얘기하고 싶어요?
Because I get it.
Loud and clear.
알겠어요. 시끄럽고 명확하게
You are rich.
You are impulsive.
당신은 부자고, 당신은 충동적이에요
And frankly, you are
the creepiest form of stalker
그리고 여태까지 내가 접해본 사람들 중에
that I have ever
had to deal with,
가장 소름끼치는 스토커에요
and believe me when
I'm telling you that that is saying a lot,
그리고 내가 지금 하고 싶은 얘기는 많지만,
And--what are you doing
to our old offices?
근데 우리 예전 사무실에서 뭐하는 짓인가요?
Hi. I'll be right back.
반가워, 금방 돌아올께
You like it? Yeah,
I'm just trying
괜찮지? 오늘밤 파티를 위해서
to liven up
the place a bit.
조금 꾸며보고 있는데
I'm hosting
an event tonight.
좋아하면 좋겠어.
A pledge drive of sorts.
Got to make
an impression, right?
인상적이야, 그렇지?
Now, what can I do for you?
그래서 무슨 일이지?
You can stop.
You can stop sending me flowers,
당장 멈춰요.내게 꽃보내느 것도 멈추고
and you can stop
texting me and calling me
내게 문자나 전화하는 것도 멈추고
and emailing me,
because I spam them, anyway.
스팸처리 해두긴 했지만 이메일 보내는 것도 멈춰요
Oh, is "spam" a verb now?
그 "스팸"은 동사를 말하는거지?
Because I am never,
ever, ever going to work for you.
왜냐하면 난 절대 절대 절대로 당신 밑에서
일할 맘은 없으니까요
Actually, you already do.
실은, 이미 날 위해 일하고 있는거야
Only because you
bought the store that I work at!
내가 일하던 그 가게를 당신이 사버린건가요
No, I didn't.
Yes, you did!
안 그랬는데
아니, 그랬어요
My boss just called
and told me that you did.
내 상사가 전화로 당신이 매장을 샀다고 알려줬으니까요
Well, he's wrong--kind of.
음, 그건 좀 와전된 거야
I bought the holding company
which owns and operates
난 2000개의 매장을 소유하고 운영하는
all 20,000 Tech Village stores.
지주사를 인수한거니까
But I guess either way,
yes, I am your boss now.
하지만 어떤 면으로는 맞아,
난 이제 네 상사지
So you can either
work for me here
그래서 넌 지금 여기 이 큰 사무실에서
in a big office
with a big salary,
많은 돈을 받으며 내 밑에서 일 하던가
or...you can work
for me there,
우스꽝스러운 유니폼을 입고서
in that awful uniform.
내 소유의 그 가게에서 일하던가 해야겠지
Or...I can quit.
혹은... 관두던가 겠지요
Which is what
I just did.
내가 방금 해버린...
You know,
그거알아,
most girls would be flattered that
I spent $1.2 billion to hire them.
대부분의 아가씨들은 내가 12억불에 고용하겠다고 하면
좋아서 어쩔줄을 몰라하고
Even if I do have a fairly genius plan
for rebranding the stores.
심지어 내가 그 가게들의 새단장하기 위한 엄청난 계획을 준비하고 있다고 하면
In case you haven't noticed,
I am not most girls.
아직 모르나본데,
난 일반적인 아가씨가 아니네요.
And I don't
need this. Or you.
그리고 난 이런 것들도 당신도 필요없어요
Or any of this.
아무것도
Felicity, I--I piss people
off on a daily basis.
Felicity, 내 내가 매일 사람들을 열받게 하는데
It's part of business,
and, well,
그건 비지니스를 위한 거고, 또
being the smartest guy
in any given room.
주어진 상황에서 어쩔 수 없이 똑똑한 척을 해야는거야
I own that. So I have enough experience
with people being angry with me
내가 그래. 그리고 사람들이 내게 진심으로 화가 났을떄
to know when they're really angry
at something else.
어떻게 하는지 많이 봐와서 알수 있어
You right now are not
angry at me.
넌 지금 내게 화가 난게 아니야
What's your something else?
다른 뭔가의 이유지?
Oh, money won't
fix this problem.
오, 돈으로 다되는 줄 알고
Money won't solve
most problems.
돈은 아무것도 해주는게 없지
Not the ones that matter.
그렇게 중요한게 아니야
But talking helps.
하지만 대화는 도움이 되지
I know we barely
know each other...
우리가 잘 모르긴 하지만...
I'm going
to leave now.
이만 가야곘어요.
Listen, whatever
happened, sorry.
들어봐, 뭐든지 간에, 미안해.
It helps to remember that...
그냥 이것만은 알아줬으면 좋겠어.
It gets better.
괜찮아질거야.
Someone was murdered here.
Tell me what you saw.
누군가 여기서 죽음을 당했어.
네가 본게 뭐지?
I saw nothing.
아무것도 못 봤어요
There was
a black face mask,
검은 마스크를 쓰고 있었어요
like a--like
a hockey mask.
꼭 하키 마스크 같은
Now, please, man--
Diggle, are you at A.R.G.U.S.?
I've got something.
Diggle, ARGUS에 도착했어?
단서가 생겼어.
Yeah, I'm here.
그래, 와있어.
I got a list of archers
20-long, man.
대략 20명 정도의 궁수 리스트를 구했어
How many of them
wear masks?
그 중 몇 명이나 마스크를 쓰지?
Only one.
단지 한 명
Simon Lacroix.
Mercenary.
용병인 Simon Lacroix.
Goes by "Komodo."
"Komodo."로 알려진
Send Felicity
everything.
Felicity에게 관련 자료를 다 보내줘
Yep.
그래
Oliver, I'm opening up
the file now.
Oliver, 지금 파일을 열어보고 있어요
Is that him?
그 놈인가?
Simon Lacroix. Born in
Saint-Sophie, Quebec.
Simon Lacroix. Quebec 지역 Saint-Sophie 출생
Raised by a single mom.
Terrible credit score.
홀어미니 밑에서 성장했고,
정말 신용도는 정말 형편없네요
Oh, and wanted
for murder in seven countries.
아 그리고 7개 나라에서 살인으로
수배중이네요
I need his location.
One minute.
그가 있는 곳을 알아야겠어
1분만 줘요
Put him on speaker.
스피커로 연결해줘요
Ok, indexing all active burner
cell phones within the city limits.
좋아요, 지금 도시내 사용되는 모든 선불폰을 검색하고있고
There's got to be
10,000 phones.
10000개는 넘을 텐데
Yes, but how many
are making calls to dear old mom
그래요, 하지만 그중 얼마나 많은 사람들이 Saint-Sophie, Quebec에 사는
in Saint-Sophie, Quebec?
노모에게 전화를 할까요?
I got him.
He's on the move.
찾았어요. 지금 이동중이에요
I found Lacroix.
Lacroix을 찾았어
I need to see
what's happening.
어떻게 되고 있는지 좀 볼께요
Ok. Blowing up
street camera feed.
그래요, 보안 카메라를 띄울께요
Come on, Ollie.
일어나, Ollie.
Get up.
Oliver?
일어나.
Are you ok?
괜찮아요?
Oliver?
He got away.
놓쳤어
I had him, Diggle.
거의 잡은거였는데, Diggle.
The way you look,
he almost had you.
내가 보기엔 네가 거의 잡힌 듯 했는데.
Where's Roy?
Roy는 어딨어?
He's out canvassing.
조사차 나갔어요
Tell me about
the driver of the car.
그 차 운전자에 대해 알려줘
His name is Erlich Kelso. He just
got out of Starling General--
이름은 Erlich Kelso. 방금 나온곳이 Starling General...
and where are we
with Lacroix?
Lacroix은 어디쯤 있지?
He ditched
his burner.
그는 가지고 있던 폰을 버렸어
I'm searching the city
for any calls made to Quebec.
Quebec으로 걸려지는 모든 통화를 추적하고 있어요
We used that to track him once;
He's not going to let it happen again.
전에도 그렇게 찾았었는데
또 그런 일이 벌어지게 두지는 않을거야
All right, so why don't we stop
searching for Lacroix
좋아 그럼 Lacroix를 찾기보다는
and start searching
for his target?
그의 다음 목표를 찾아보는게 어때?
Because there must be a connection
with his victims.
어쨌건 피해자와 뭔가 커넥션이 있을거야
Already on it.
이미 알아보고 있어요
I mean, what if we just--
we go to a local morgue
내 말은, 우리가 주변 영안실로 가서
and we find a body
that looks like Tommy's?
Tommy와 비슷한 시체를 찾아보면 어떨까 싶다는 거야
At the Hong Kong morgue?
홍콩 영안실에서?
You've got a better chance
of winning the lottery
차라리 로또에 당첨되서
and trying to pay Waller off.
Waller를 매수하는게 빠르겠군.
I am not going
to assassinate my best friend,
나 내 절친을 암살하지 않을거야
do you understand?
There has to be another way.
알겠어?
뭔가 다른 방법이 있을거라구
There is.
있어
But it involves
Amanda Waller
그렇지만 Amanda Waller를 끌어들이고
finding someone else
to execute your friend.
널 대신해 친구를 죽일 사람을 찾게 될거야
No, not you, Dad.
Look, I'm already in Hong Kong.
아뇨, 아빠 말구요.
전 이미 Hong Kong에 있다구요
No! No, I didn't tell you
I was taking the jet
아뇨, 아뇨 제가 제트기를 타고 오면
because I knew you would
freak out like this.
이렇게 질겁하실 줄 알아서 말씀 안드린 거에요
No, I don't know how long, ok?
It doesn't matter.
아뇨, 언제까지 있을지 모르고 상관없어요. 아시겠어요?
Listen, if Oliver is still alive,
if he is still here--
만약 Oliver가 살아있고, 여기에 있다면
Look, why don't you just go back
to banging your Pilates instructor, ok?
여보세요, 그냥 전화끊고 요가 강사랑 뒹굴기나 하시라구요.
I'll just be here searching
for my best friend.
난 여기서 내 절친을 찾기위해 있을거야
I'm sorry, miss.
You can't go in there.
죄송합니다. 아가씨,
들어가실 수 없습니다.
Laurel Lance. I'm with the district
attorney's office.
검사 사무실에서 온 Laurel Lance예요
Erlich Kelso
is a witness
Erlich Kelso는 현재 수사 중인 사건의
of my ongoing
investigation.
중요 목격자에요
Mr. Kelso's under
protective custody.
Kelso는 보호 구금 중에 있습니다.
Not from me. And if you have
a problem with that,
내겐 아니죠, 만약 불만이 있다면
you can call
your captain.
당신 서장님에게 전화해 보세요
Tell him his
daughter says hello.
서장님 딸이 안부 전해달라고 했다고
Who are you?
누구요?
I work in the DA's office.
검사측에서 왔어요.
I already
told the police,
난 이미 경찰에게 진술했어요
I don't know
anything.
아무것도 모른다고
I still have to ask you
a few questions.
몇 가지 질문만 하겠어요
Why isn't this working?
It is.
이건 왜 동작하지 않지?
동작해요
It's running an NSA
algorithm aggregating
공식, 비공식의 모든 정부기관의 데이타 베이스를 참조해서
the victims' personal
information using
피해자의 개인정보를 국토안보국에서 개발한
every government database
known, and unknown.
알고리즘으로 분석하고 있어요
Well, it's taking too long.
Sara's killer is still out there,
근데, 너무 오래 걸리는 걸
우리가 여기서 이렇게 시간을 낭비하는 동안
which means that every minute that
we waste down here--
Sara를 죽인 살인자는 아직도 활보하고 있는데
I know! You don't
need to tell me
알아요! 내가 모른다는 것처럼
as if I don't already know.
굳이 다시 얘기할 필요 없어요
You're right.
옳아.
And I apologize.
사과할께
I just need your a game
right now, Felicity.
난 지금 네가 필요해, Felicity.
I don't have it!
나도 힘들어요!
My friend--our friend--
내 친구, 우리 친구가
was shot with arrows
and fell off of a rooftop.
옥상에서 화살을 맞아 옥상에서 떨어지고
Her body is upstairs
right above us in a freezer
그녀 시신은 우리 바로 위 냉동실에 있어요
because we don't know
what to do with it--
왜냐하면 우린 지금 그녀의 시신을 어떻게 해야할지
with her.
모르니까요
So I am so sorry, Oliver,
그래서 나도 슬퍼요, Oliver,
if I have feelings, but maybe
if you did, too, we...
만약 당신도 그녀처럼 죽었을거라고 생각하면, 우린...
Sorry.
미안해요.
That was mean. But this is Sara
we're talking about.
좀 심했어요. 어쨌건 우리가 얘기하는 건 Sara지요
Your Sara.
당신의 Sara.
How can you stand there
being so cold
어떻게 그렇게 냉정하고 이성적으로
and rational?
있을 수 있나요?
'Cause I don't have the luxury
of falling to pieces.
왜냐하면 난 그런 사치스런 감정을 가질 수 없으니까
Everyone's looking to me
to handle things,
모두가 내가 올바른 결정을 내릴 수 있도록
to make the right
decisions.
도와주기를 바라고
Everyone
is looking to me...
모두가 내가 이끌어주기를
to lead.
바라니까
If I grieve,
내가 슬픔에 빠지면
nobody else gets to.
아무도 대신할 사람이 없어지나까
You're still
a human being, Oliver.
당신도 사람이에요, Oliver.
You're allowed to have feelings.
감정을 가질 수 있는 사람이에요
I know sometimes
that it's easier
Hood를 뒤집어쓰고 산다는게
to live under that hood.
어떤 의미인지 알지만
I'm not.
모르겠어
Earlier today,
I was looking at Sara,
오늘 아침에 난 Sara를 찾았었어
I realized something.
뭐가를 깨달았었지
One of these days
it's going to be me.
요즘 같은 날들은 내게 벌어졌어야 해
And this...
이런 것들이
This life that
I've chosen...
내가 선택한 이런 삶들이
It only ends one way.
결국엔 한 귀결로 흐르겠지
So that's it?
그래서 그게 단가요?
You're just going
to spend your life
단지 죽음을 맞이하기 위해
hiding down here
in this cave,
여기 지하의 어두운 곳에서
waiting to die?
I'm sorry.
인생과 시간을 보내고 있는 건가요?
미안한데요.
I'm not going
to wait with you,
난 당신과 함께 맞이하진 않을거에요
because if there's one thing that
today has taught me,
왜냐하면 오늘 있었던 일에서 내가 배운건
is that life is precious.
삶은 귀중하다는 거니까요
And I want so much more
in mine than this.
그래서 내 삶에서 지금보다 더 많은 것들을 원해요
Let's start
with the obvious.
다시 한 번 정리해 보지요
Why would someone
want to kill you?
왜 다른 누군가가 당신이 죽기를 바랄까요?
I have no idea.
모르겠소
This whole thing,
it's insane.
이 모든게, 미쳐돌아가는게지
Mr. Kelso, despite
what you may have heard,
Mr. Kelso, 무슨말을 들었던지 간에
homicides at the hands
of a stranger
타인의 손에 의한 살인미수는 의외로
are incredibly rare.
정말로 드물어요
Imagine how rare homicides
by bow and arrow are.
활과 화살에 의한 살인미수는 어떨까요?
Yeah, the guy
was a sicko.
그래, 그 사내는 미친놈 갔았어
And you're a liar.
그리고 당신은 거짓말장이구요.
I'm the victim here.
You're also a witness--
난 피해자라구.
동시에 증인이기도 하지요
my witness. And you better
give me something useful,
당신이 저지른 일로 기소되기 싫다면, 증인으로서
otherwise you're going to be
facing an obstruction charge.
뭔가 유용한 정보를 제공해봐요
You know, I think I want
to talk to your boss,
이봐요, 날 이렇게 대하겠다면
because you can't
treat people like this.
난 아무래도 당신 상관과 얘기해야 겠소
Oh, really, you want
to talk to my boss?
오 그래요? 내 상관과 얘기하고 싶으시다?
Ohh!
How's your arm feeling?!
팔의 느낌은 어때?!
What are you doing?!
뭐 하는 짓이야?!
John Burke and Tim Kaufman,
John Burke 와 Tim Kaufman,
they were also shot by
with arrows.
둘다 화살에 맞아 살해당했어
And they're too dead
to tell me why.
이유를 말해주기엔 이미 늦었지
Can't.
안돼
Ohh!
Burke and Kaufman!
Burke 와 Kaufman!
What do the two of them
have to do with you?
그들과 무슨 관계지?
We were all
working on a deal!
예전에 같이 일을 했었어
But nobody was supposed
to know about it.
하지만 아무도 모를텐데
Ohh! Ohh.
What kind of deal?
어떤 일?
To build
an oil pipe line.
Amertek를 위한 송유관을 매설하는
For Amertek. It's--
작업이었어. 그건..
You've reached Thea.
Leave a message.
Thea 입니다. 메시지를 남겨주세요.
Hey, Thea, it's me. Again.
여보세요, Thea, 또 나야
And...I don't know
if you're getting these messages,
어.. 니가 이 메시지를 듣는지는 모르겠지만
but I would really
like to talk to you.
정말로 네 목소리가 듣고싶어
So please, just...
그러니 제발..
call me back.
전화 줘
Bye.
안녕.
Lyla has multiple teams trying to get
an angle on Lacroix.
Lyla가 Lacroix를 찾기위해 여러 인원을 투입했어
Where's Felicity?
Felicity는 어딨지?
Hmm.
She needed some air.
잠깐 바람쐬러 간듯해
And what do you
need, Oliver?
넌 왜 그래 Oliver?
I just need Thea
to call me back.
나는 Thea가 전화를 줬으면 좋겠어
That's not going
to happen.
그럴 일은 없을거에요
Why? What do you mean?
왜? 무슨 의미야??
It was during the siege.
전에 경찰에 쫓길때
We were going to run away together,
but I couldn't leave
우린 같이 도망가고 있었어요.
하지만, 난 당신이 싸우는 걸 돕느라
without helping you fight.
돌아와야 했어요
And when I came back,
she was gone.
그리고 다시 그 곳에 갔을때,
그녀는 사라졌어요
I didn't say anything
because this is my fault.
모두가 내 잘못이라 Thea에게 말하지는 않았지만
She knew I was lying
to her the entire time.
그녀는 늘 내가 거짓을 말했던 걸 알았던 듯 해요
I'm sorry I didn't
say anything about the letter.
편지에 대해 미리 말씀 못 드려 죄송해요
I know that
I should have.
진작 보여드렸어야 했는데
Ok.
Felicity, I really
need to talk to you,
Felicity 나 정말 당신이 필요해
so please, can you...
Call me back as soon as you get this.
그러니 제발... 이 메시지를 듣거든 전화해줘
Urel! Baby,
are you all right?
Laurel!
별일 없니?
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
다친건 아니고?
괜찮아요
Baby, a guy just
got skewered right in front of you.
얘야, 방금 네 앞에서 사람이 죽었다고 들어서
I hope
you're not fine.
너도 어떻게 됐나 걱정했단다
And what the hell were you
doing here in the first place?
애초에 도대체 여기는 뭐하러 온게냐?
The district attorney's office--
검사측에서는
did not send you.
널 보낸적 없다던데
You lied to my officers
and now what,
넌 경찰관들에게 거짓말을 했었고 지금은
you're just going
to stand there
여기 이렇게 서서는
and you're going
to lie to me?
내게 거짓말을 해?
I needed to talk to him.
It was important.
전 중요한 일로 그와 얘기해야 했어요
Look, sweetie,
I know you want to help,
이봐, 얘야, 네가 돕고 싶어하는 건 알겠다
but you don't need to take
these kind of risks,
하지만 네가 이 모든 위험을 감수할 필요는 없단다
you understand?
Pretty sure your sister's
알겠니?
got that covered
for the both of you.
전에도 네 동생이 널 위해 보호해주지 않았으면 어땠었겠니
Yeah.
네
Go home.
We got this.
집에 가려무나. 이젠부턴 내가 맡으마
Ok?
I've got something.
Meet me at Verdant.
단서를 찾았어요. Verdant에서 만나요.
Amertek industries.
It's an oil company
based in Starling City.
스탈링 시티에 기반을 둔 정유회사예요
Ok. Now that
I've consolidated
그래요, 지금 Lacroix에게 살해된
all of Lacroix's
victim's records,
피해자들 정보를 취합하고 있어요
I can run the algorithm,
scan the data
알고리즘과 데이타를 스캔해서
and see who received
money from Amertek.
Amertek에서 돈을 받은게 누군지 확인할께요
How long does that take?
Not long.
얼마나 걸릴까요?
오래 걸리지 않을거에요.
Three to Kelso, one more to Burke,
two more to Kaufman.
Qurac에 있는 Amertek의 지사에서
All from a subsidiary
from Amertek in Qurac,
Kelso, Burke, Kaufman 모두 돈을 받았었군
which just happens to be the largest
untapped oil field on the planet.
지구에서 가장큰 산유지를 가진 Amertek라...
Yeah. Looks like Amertek was trying
to strike an oil deal.
그래, Amertek은 기름 거래에 혁명을 가져오려 했던 듯하고
And some paid Lacroix
to stop it.
누군가 Lacroix 에게 멈추는 댓가로 돈을 지불한거지
None of this explains
how Sara was involved.
Sara가 어떻게 연관됐는지는 모르겠어
Sara once told me
she worked in Qurac.
Sara 가 전에 Qurac에서 일한적 있다고 헀었어요
And by "worked," I mean she killed
people for the League.
그리고 "일한적," 이란건 League를 위해 누군가를 죽였단 거겠죠
You're saying she might have brought
her work home with her.
네 말은 그녀가 뭔가 마무리되지 않은채 돌아왔다는 건가?
Who authorized the payments?
누가 지불을 승인했지?
A board member of Amertek
called Tom Westin.
Amertek 이사회 중 한 명인 Tom Westin 이네요
He's Lacroix's next target.
What's his location?
그가 Lacroix의 다음 목표야. 어디에 있지?
You will not believe
where he's headed.
그가 어디로 가고있는지 알면 놀랄거에요
Where do you think
you're going?
어디 가려는거야?
I'm coming with you.
Absolutely not.
너와 함께 가겠어
절대로 안돼
Oliver, the only reason why you know
where to find him is because--
Oliver, 당신이 그가 어딨는지 알려는 이유는 오직
You were reckless. And Lacroix
almost put an arrow in you.
넌 너무 무모해. 그리고 Lacroix 화살에 거의 죽을뻔 했어
Let me handle this.
내가 알아서 하겠어
don't you dare tell me
to stay put and think that I'll listen!
니가 그런다고 내가 가만히 앉아서 말듣고 있을 줄 알아?
You know me better than that.
나에 대해 잘 알텐데?
Sara was trained by some
of the greatest killers in human history.
Sara는 인간 역사상 가장 유명한 살인자 단체에서 훈련받았어
Lacroix put her down.
Lacroix 는 그녀를 쓰러뜨렸지
So what do you think
he's going to do to you?
그런 그가 너에겐 어떻겠어?
I don't care about anything
except for getting him.
난 그를 잡는 거 외에는 상관안해
And I will.
You couldn't before!
내가 상관해.
전에 너도 놓쳤잖아.
I won't let him
escape again.
다신 그를 놓치지 않을거야
I promise.
약속할께
I won't let him
escape again.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Ray Palmer.
신사 숙녀 여러분,
Thank you. Thank you all
for coming out tonight.
감사합니다. 이자리를 빛내주신 모든 분들께 감사드립니다.
Given all that has
befallen this city,
이 도시에 발생했던 모든 재앙들이,
it's easy for us to lose hope--
우리의 희망을 앗아갔고
to hide in our castles
움츠려 들게 했지만
and be thankful that our
ledges are in the black.
우린 그로부터 굳건히 헤쳐나왔습니다.
Well, we, the city's most affluent
businessmen and women
우리, 도시의 가장 훌륭한 사업가인 신사 숙녀 여러분
hold its future in our hands.
우리의 미래를 우리 손으로 이루어냅시다
Tonight, I'm making a pledge.
오늘 밤, 나는 공표하겠습니다.
I will give away
half of my net worth
우리 도시의 발전을 위해
to the benefit of our home.
내 재산의 절반을 기부하고,
And this will be my salary
for the year.
그리고 이게 앞으로 내 월급이 될겁니다.
So tonight, I invite you all
to join me in this investment.
오늘밤, 이자리에 모인 여러분들도 함꼐 동참해 주시기 바랍니다.
Not just with your money,
but with your ingenuity,
여러분의 돈보다는, 여러분만의 능력을
and most importantly,
your time.
그리고 무엇보다 중요한, 여러분의 시간을
The city is my home,
but it's yours, too.
이 도시는 내 집이자, 여러분의 것이기도 합니다.
So help make Star City
our future.
그러니 스타시티의 미래를 위해 도와주십시오
Let go of the arrow.
덤벼라
I thought
you'd be taller.
좀 더 클줄 알았는데
It's over.
끝났어
Lower your bow and live.
활을 거둬라
We both know
that's not going to happen.
그럴일이 없다는거 서로 알잖아?
Who hired you?!
Who's she?
누가 널 고용했지?!
그녀는 누구지?
You don't want
to do this.
이러면 안 돼
Yes, I do!
아니, 돼
Killing him
won't bring her back.
그를 죽인다고 Sara가 돌아오지 않아
I know it won't bring
her back, she's dead!
그녀는 죽었으니까, 다시 돌아올 수 없다는 건 알아
I have stood where
you are right now;
나도 네 입장에 선 적이 있었어
where you're so consumed
with rage you can
거친 숨과 함께 분노를 느끼면서
hardly breathe,
and you think that
복수하는게 당연한 행동이라
taking revenge
will make it better,
느껴지겠지
but Laurel...it won't.
하지만 Laurel, 그렇지 않아
It only makes it worse.
그건 더욱 더 상황을 나쁘게 할 뿐이야.
No, he murdered Sara!
아니, 그가 Sara를 죽였어!
Who's Sara?
Sara가 누구지?
My sister, you son of a bitch!
내 여동생이다 이 XX야!
Two nights ago,
이틀 전날 밤
you put an arrow in her chest.
네가 그녀의 심장을 화살로 꿰뚫었지
Two nights ago
이틀 전날 밤
I was drunk
in Bludhaven.
난 블루헤븐에서 술마시고 있었어
You're lying.
I'm proud of my work.
거짓말 마.
난 내 일에 자부심을 느껴
I wouldn't deny it.
내가 한 일을 부인하지 않지
Even with a gun in your face?
네 얼굴에 총구를 들이밀어도?
Laurel, you need to stop
and listen to him.
Laurel, 그만 멈추고 이자 말을 들어봐
No.
싫어.
No, he killed my sister.
싫어, 그가 내 여동생을 죽였어
Laurel, Sara
wouldn't want--
Laurel, Sara 도 원하지 않을거야
Don't you dare tell me
Sara가 원하지 않을거란 그런 말
that this isn't what
Sara would have wanted!
꺼내지도 말아
Don't you tell me
to think of her,
그녀가 그립단 말도 하지 말아
because I am
thinking of her!
왜냐면 정말 그녀를 그리는 건 나니까
Laurel, if you pull
that trigger--
Laurel, 니가 만약 방아쇠를 당긴다면..
You took the bullets
out of the gun!
니가 총알을 빼버렸구나
We have to go.
우린 가야해.
Lacroix's alibi
checks out.
Lacroix의 알리바이는 확인됐어요
Two murders in
Bludhaven, same MO.
블루헤븐에서 같은 수법의 두건의 살인
Same night
Sara was killed.
그 날 밤, Sara가 죽었었고
I almost killed Lacroix.
내가 Lacroix를 죽일뻔 했는데
The only thing that
matters is you didn't.
중요한건 니가 그러지 않았다는 거야
Laurel...
the trail's
run cold.
진정해
I'm going to find
whoever did this.
누가 그랬든지 내가 찾아낼거야
I will.
반드시
But I don't know when.
그게 언제인지 알수는 없지만
Your father
deserves to know.
이제 네 아버지도 아셔야 할 것 같아
Hey, listen.
여보세요
I got some word on the boy.
Yeah, some stuff's come through.
그 놈한테 몇가지 정보를 얻었지
그래, 뭐 쓸데없는 것들도 있었지만
I don't know. Yeah.
It looks pretty good.
잘 모르겠어, 그래, 괜찮은 듯해
Lacroix, with an "x."
Yeah. I don't know, the guy's French
Lacroix, "x."라니
그래, 나도 몰라, 그 놈은 프랑스인이라구
or something,
why you asking--
혹은 뭐. 왜 물어보는거야?
Oh, hold on, hold on.
I got to call you back.
아 잠깐, 잠깐
내가 다시 걸께
Laurel, baby, what's wrong?
Laurel, 얘야 무슨 일이니?
Hold on.
잠시만
What is it?
무슨 일이니?
Just tell me.
Tell me, what is it?
말해보렴, 무슨 일이니??
It's about last night.
지난 밤에
At the hospital.
병원에서
I lied to you.
제가 거짓말을 했었어요
And you deserve to know
the truth, and--
그리고 아버지께 진실을 말씀드리고 싶어요. 그래서..
Sorry, sweetheart.
미안하구나, 얘야
Damn thing goes off every hour
if I don't take my pills.
매시간 이놈의 약을 먹지 않으면 이모양이구나
Laurel, what do you know?
You looked like you were
Laurel, 무슨 일이니?
그날도 뭔가 내게 말할지
in the middle
of telling me something.
말지를 고민하는 듯 하더니
I just wanted
to say that...
이 말씀을 드리고 싶어요...
That I'm really sorry.
정말 죄송해요
I know that I should
have told you the truth,
아버지께 진실을 말씀드렸어야는건 알았는데
I just...
전 단지
I just got to--
전 단지 그랬어야...
Hey, I'm your dad.
얘야, 난 네 애비란다.
I forgive you.
널 용서하마
Come here.
이리 오렴
I always forgive you.
난 항상 널 용서한단다
It's all right.
다 괜찮아
She can rest now.
이제 편히 쉴 수 있을거야
She's home.
집에 돌아왔으니
It's a Jewish custom.
유태교 전통이에요
I know she wasn't,
그녀가 아닌건 알지만
but it feels right.
왠지 이게 맞는 듯 해요
Laurel.
No, this isn't right.
아냐, 이건 옳지 않아
This isn't--
이건...
It--she doesn't even
get a fresh grave?
Sara는 그녀의 무덤에도 묻힐 수 없는거야?
It's so perverse.
이건 정말 아니야
She deserves a proper burial.
Sara는 이렇게 보내줘야 해
She's earned it.
그녀도 바랬을거야
No, it's not fair.
아냐, 불공평해
No one will ever
really know who she was.
누구도 그녀가 진정 어떤 사람인지 알 수 없을거야
Oliver, it's not fair.
Oliver, 옳지않아
It's not fair!
이건 옳지않아!
Laurel, we'll know.
Laurel, 우리가 기억할거야
I know this doesn't
count for much,
큰 의미가 없을 수도 있겠지만
but me and Lyla,
we're naming the baby Sara.
나와 Lyla,
우리 아이 이름을 Sara로 지을거야
We will never forget.
우리가 절대 잊지 않도록
Thank you.
고마워
How did I--
내가 어떻게...
what the hell
is going on here?
도대체 무슨 일이야?
Where am I?
여긴 어디지?
Please, please don't--
please don't hurt me.
제발 안돼, 제발 나를 해치지 말아줘
Just--just
let me go, please.
그냥.. 그냥 보내줘 제발.
I promise, I--I won't
tell anybody about this.
아무한테도 얘기하지 않겠다고 맹세할께
Would a fisherman throw his
prized catch back into the sea?
낚시꾼이 한 번 잡은 물고기를 놓아줄까?
What
are you talking about?
무슨 얘길 하는거야?
Look, whoever you are,
이봐, 니가 누구던지간에,
you really don't
want to do this.
정말 이러면 안돼는 거야
Do you have any idea who
I am? Who my father is?!
내가 누군지 알아? 우리 아버지가 누군지 알아?!
You're Thomas Merlyn.
넌 Thomas Merlyn이지
You've been looking
for Oliver Queen.
Oliver Queen을 찾아 여기 왔고
How--how do you--
how do you know that?
그걸 그걸 어떻게?
A simple hack of a missing
billionaire's email account.
사라진 억망장자의 이메일을 해킹하는 건 쉬운 일이지
I knew somebody would come
looking for him,
그러면 누군가 걸려들 줄 알았어
but I thought it would be
his...Mother.
그의 어머니가 올 줄 알았는데
His sister.
But you, the son
그의 동생이나...
근데 Merlyn Global 사장 아들인
of the CEO of Merlyn Global.
니가 오다니
Jackpot.
My friend,
you are going to make me
이제 니가 네개 큰 돈을
a very rich man.
벌어주게 되겠군
So Oliver didn't...
그러면 Oliver는..
He isn't...
그는..
Oliver Queen is dead.
Oliver Queen은 죽었어
He's rotting at the bottom
of the ocean.
바다 바닥에서 썩어나가고 있겠지
And you will, too,
그리고 너도, 그렇게 될거고
if your father doesn't
pay that ransom.
네 아버지가 몸값을 내지 않는다면..
I'm in here,
please help! Help!
나 여기 있어요. 제발 도와주세요.
Police! Hong Kong police!
It's ok.
Thank you!
You're going home.
You're safe now.
당신은 집에 보내질 겁니다.
이제 안전해요.
I'm going to catch
whoever killed her.
Sara를 죽인게 누군지 간에 반드시 잡을거야.
I know you are.
네가 해내리라 믿어
And until you do,
I'm back on the team.
그리고 그 때까지, 나도 팀에서 함께하겠어
What about
your family?
가족들은 어쩌고?
Sara is family,
Oliver.
Sara 도 가족이야
Just like you,
man.
너 처럼
So now what?
그래서 이젠 어떻게 할까?
Now I got to go get Thea.
난 Thea를 데리러 가야겠어.
It's long past time
she came home.
그녀를 떠나보낸지 너무 오래됐어
John.
I don't want
to die down here.
난 이곳에서 죽는 건 싫어
So don't, Oliver.
그럼 그러지마, Oliver.
??Man wasn't made
to live alone ??
??that's why I have
my enemies ??
??whenever I close my eyes ??
??you're all I can see ??
??every man needs a savior ??
??every savior needs his task ??
??but which one am I ??
??the man or the one
behind the mask ??
??what comes first ??
??courage or the fall ??
Hey.
이봐.
Hi.
안녕하세요.
You changed your mind?
생각이 바뀐거야?
I just decided I want
more out of life.
보다 나은 길로 살아가야겠다고 다짐했어
Well done.
Thanks, Dad.
고마워요, 아버지.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man